Cooperative Extension Service Agronomy Specialist (Morrison) Records 1955-1969
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Cooperative Extension Service Agronomy Specialist (Morrison) Records
1955-1969
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections Pullman, WA 99164-5610 USA (509) 335-6691 http://www.wsulibs.wsu.edu/masc/ mascref@wsu.edu
Archives 30
approximate 3200 items 4 linear feet 4 containers
Consists mainly of the correspondence of Kenneth Morrison, relating to communication with other County Extension agents, as well as home gardeners and farmers.
Organizational Sketch:
The origin of the Co-operative Extension Service can be traced to a 1913 act by the Washington State Legislature which created the Bureau of Farm Development and provided for agricultural experts to assist farmers. The federal Smith-Lever Act of 1914 lent financial support to the state's program and placed the director of Extension Services directly under the auspices of the land grant college.
In 1917 President E.O. Holland appointed the first agronomy extension specialist whose duties were to act as disseminator of agricultural research data to the county agents and the public. In 1950 the present incumbent, Kenneth J. Morrison, came to Washington State University to fill the position of agronomy extension specialist. Born in 1921, Morrison received his BA in 1948 from Kansas State University, and his MA and PhD from Purdue in 1950 and 1967 respectively.
The records of the Agronomy Specialist consist almost entirely of the correspondence of Kenneth J. Morrison. Although there are only two series, the first (general correspondence) contains the bulk of the material. Of the two subseries within series one, the first is organized alphabetically by correspondent for each year 1961 through 1969. The second subseries is a subject file of correspondence and memoranda arranged alphabetically by topic which spans the years 1955 through 1969. The second series, consisting of correspondence between Morrison and county agents throughout Washington State, is arranged by county within annual groupings from 1961 through 1968. Correspondents, while including media and industry representatives, county agents, and agricultural specialists, consist principally of home gardeners and farmers concerned with plant identification and extension publications.
The Collection is open for research use.
The records of the Washington State University Extension Agronomy Specialist were placed in the Washington State University Libraries by Kenneth J. Morrison in June 1978 (UA 78-17).
Morrison, Kenneth J.--Archives
Washington State University. Cooperative Extension Service. Agronomy Specialist--Archives; Washington State University. Extension Service.; State College of Washington. Extension Service.; Washington State University. Cooperative Extension Service. Agronomy Specialist--Records and correspondence
Agricultural extension work--Washington (State)--Archives; Agriculture--Washington (State)--Archives
Washington (State); Colleges and Universities; Agriculture
- General Correspondence, 1
  - A-Z, 1962; 365 items (Box 1, Folder 1-23)
  - A-Z, 1963; 225 items (Box 1, Folder 24-46)
  - A-Z, 1964; 230 items (Box 1, Folder 47-70)
  - A-Z, 1965-1966; 480 items (Box 2, Folder 71-92)
  - A-Z, 1967-1968; 530 items (Box 2, Folder 93-116)
  - A-Z, 1969; 255 items (Box 3, Folder 117-138)
  - Bertramson, B.R., 1965-1967; 25 items (Box 3, Folder 139)
  - Correspondence, 1967-1969; 10 items (Box 3, Folder 140)
  - Cosgriffe, H.A., 1964-1966; 12 items (Box 3, Folder 141)
  - Cytogenetics, 1955; 1 item (Box 3, Folder 142)
  - Duplicates, 1963-1964; 55 items (Box 3, Folder 143-144)
  - Fertilizer Conference, 1963; 1 item (Box 3, Folder 145)
  - Genetics, 1958-1963; 15 items (Box 3, Folder 146)
  - Herbicide Advisory Council, 1963; 2 items (Box 3, Folder 147)
  - Isotopes, 1959-1960; 3 items (Box 3, Folder 148)
  - Land File, 1963-1964; 5 items (Box 3, Folder 149)
  - Memoranda, 1962-1963; 15 items (Box 3, Folder 150-151)
  - Memoranda to Agents, 1965-1969; 80 items (Box 3, Folder 152-155)
  - Outlying Testing- Central Washington, 1963; 5 items (Box 3, Folder 156)
  - Outlying Testing- Western Washington, 1963; 10 items (Box 3, Folder 157)
  - Plant Materials Center, 1963; 2 items (Box 3, Folder 158)
  - Seed House, 1963; 5 items (Box 3, Folder 159)
  - Storage Space, 1963; 5 items (Box 3, Folder 160)
  - Scholarships, 1963; 25 items (Box 3, Folder 161)
  - Soil Improvement Committee, 1963; 25 items (Box 3, Folder 162-163)
  - Tri-State Wheat Researchers Conference, 1963; 1 item (Box 3, Folder 164)
  - Washington State Crop Improvement Association, 1963; 5 items (Box 3, Folder 165)
  - Wheat Plotland Exemptions, 1962-1963; 15 items (Box 3, Folder 166)
  - Wheat Quality, 1963; 10 items (Box 3, Folder 167)
- County Agent Correspondence (by county), 2
  - 1962, 185 items (Box 3, Folder 168-201)
  - 1963, 160 items (Box 4, Folder 202-239)
  - 1964, 175 items (Box 4, Folder 236-266)
  - 1965-1966, 215 items (Box 4, Folder 267-297)
  - 1967-1968, 235 items (Box 4, Folder 298-323)